# Oleksandr Oharkov

Kyiv, Kyiv City, Ukraine

zhasmin701@gmail.com

linkedin.com/in/angelprodev-7b816027a

## **Summary**

Experienced web and mobile Full-Stack Developer with 7+ years of experience building projects from the ground up, including design, development, and deployment. Skilled at finding the processes and tools for a project that will deliver an excellent product to end-user while being frugal with time.

My professional skills are:

- Frontend: HTML, CSS, Javascript, Bootstrap, Sass, React/Redux, Typescript, Vue, Angular
- Backend: Nodejs, Python, C#, Golang, PHP
- Database: MongoDB, MySQL, PostgreSQL, Firebase
- Devops: Jenkins, Docker, Kubernetes, GCP, Git, Azure

Individually, we are weak branches, but together we form an unbreakable tree. Let's make a better world!

## **Experience**



### Full Stack Developer

**Emerline** 

Feb 2021 - Jul 2023 (2 years 6 months)

- Developed dynamic and responsive user interfaces using modern front-end frameworks like React.js and Vue.js. Implemented user-centric features, ensuring an optimal and engaging user experience.
- Engineered scalable and efficient server-side applications designing RESTful APIs to seamlessly integrate front-end functionalities with backend systems. Employed best practices for data modeling, security, and performance optimization.
- Designed, implemented, and optimized relational and NoSQL databases to support the application's data requirements.
- Implemented CI/CD pipelines, streamlining the release process. Worked with Docker for containerization, ensuring consistency across development and production environments.
- Built an Al-powered tool for detecting and confirming the presence of faces and other data in a piece of video footage.

#### ● Full Stack Developer

Lime Global

Nov 2018 - Oct 2020 (2 years)

- Designed the web infrastructure and business logic for the betting platform and developed.
- Developed several back-end services in a REST paradigm and common infrastructure of the platform based on a microservices approach.
- Changed monolithic services to microservices architecture. Added security configurations for AWS.
- Built an integration with a third-party identity verification solution to ensure that agents on the platform are verified and no fraudulent user accounts are created.

- Improved the team's dynamics through pair-programming sessions, mentoring, and coaching fellow developers.

# Frontend Developer

Trio

Oct 2017 - Sep 2018 (1 year)

- Translated the design team's UX wireframes and mockups into responsive, interactive features.
- Provided strategic advisory on design and development processes, initiating revamped structures and systems to ensure a consistently high level of quality.
- Researched, established, documented, and maintained company coding best practices, development organization, and workflow standards.
- Delegated tasks to a full-stack team and took the initiative to provide ongoing training and coaching to junior developers to build capacity within the organization.
- Worked with the agile team to migrate a legacy company website to React and Sass.

#### **Education**



### Taras Shevchenko National University of Kyiv

Bachelor's degree, Computer Science Sep 2013 - Aug 2017

#### **Skills**

PHP • Ruby • jQuery • AWS S3 • Golang • Vue.js • React.js • AngularJS • C# • Python (Programming Language)